ALLEN LI

Beijing, China | 18210473070 | allen.li.salesforce@gmail.com in-

SUMMARY

A certificated salesforce developer with 6+ years experience & 4×Certifications for salesforce project architect, salesforce solution consultant, force.com development, large system integration with SAP(IC, BW, etc.). I have worked on 10+ salesforce projects and implemented lots of business requirements for various industries.

I'm passionate for my salesforce career and ready to take any challenges. As a big fan of salesforce and web front-end technologies, I built Metaforce/MetaforceWidgets which are amazing salesforce development/deployment tools to improve work efficiency.

Technical Specialties:

- Salesforce standard function configuration(Sales/Service Cloud) | Excellent
- Salesforce force.com Development(Apex/Pages/Batch, etc) | Excellent
- Salesforce API Integration with SAP BW/IC/Finance system(SOAP, REST, Bulk) | Excellent
- Salesforce Metadata & System Migrations (Tooling API, Metadata API, Ant) | Excellent
- Continuous Integration(Jenkins + Github/GitLab/Bitbucket + Ant) | Excellent
- Salesforce Lightning Experience & Application & Component Development | Good
- Web Development(HTML/CSS/JS + JQuery + Bootstrap + AngularJs + NodeJs + Grunt) | Good

Project Experience:

- Team Lead, Technical Consultant, SCRUM Development as Master
- Salesforce Development Flow Control, Code Version Control (GIT)
- Collaborate with global team members and managers

Certifications:

- Salesforce Certified Administrator
- Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I (401)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sony Global Information System

Salesforce Technical Leader & Team Leader | 2014.12 - 2016.01 & 2017.03 - Now

Projects: Sony VIP System | Audit Tracker

The Salesforce VIP System is a core system to help global price manager & key account manager to build pricing and market investment plan for global market.

Responsibilities:

- Analyze and Provide technical solutions for business requirement, assist solution manager to build better solutions to solve business problems
- Provide all integration scheme and technical details between Salesforce and SAP(BW, IC, iShop, Finance, etc.)
- Build project plan and break down development tasks, control project progress with GIT
- Collaborate with Dev & Global team to solve user ticket & technical issues & business feedback
- Release Management (RFC, Release Version & Note, Copado Deployment Tool)
- Apex/Visualforce/Interface Development

Tujia

Salesforce Senior Consultant | 2016.01 - 2017.2

Projects: Tujia | TuYuan Salesforce Systems

<u>Tujia Sales Management System</u> is a standard sales system. For sales reps, they can manage their customers and opportunities more efficient (Account, Opportunity, Contract, etc); For sales managers, they can check all sales data and get accurate forecast data in real time (Approval, Report, Forecast).

Responsibilities:

- Manage business requirement and TUJIA Sales Organization
- Implements customized function to track sales activities
- Design new salesforce system based on company business flow
- Migrate system and data between salesforce organizations
- System Integration with OA system to exchange contract and payment information

Meginfo

Salesforce Developer | 2012.06 – 2014.12

Projects: WhiteHat | Snapbi | Costume Manager

Responsibilities:

- Customize portal site and implement business requirements with visual force page
- Improve customer service level with Web to Lead, Web to Case, Live Agent, Salesforce Entitlement Management
- Optimize internal salesforce system with front-end technologies (Bootstrap, JQuery, Html + Css, Grunt)

Metaforce – a lightweight salesforce IDE | Personal Project

<u>Metaforce</u> is a lightweight salesforce IDE. Based on front-end technologies, Metaforce builds a modern and elegant UI to provide powerful features (Login Management, Code Editor, Deployment and Test) for salesforce development.

Metaforce Deployer | Personal Project

Salesforce Deployer provides a quite easy way to login and deploy salesforce metadata quickly.

EDUCATION

Luoyang Normal University | Bachelor's degree | Computer Science | 2008 – 2012